It's 8:14 am on August 6, 1945, and you’re about to live through hell.
1945年8月6日上午8:14，您将度过难关。
But for now, a brilliant, clear day is getting started.
但是目前，辉煌，晴朗的一天已经开始。
Morning traffic and crowded streetcars go by, and you arrive at work--a large, modern
早上的交通和拥挤的有轨电车经过，您便可以上班了-宽敞，现代
office building.
办公楼。
Earlier in the morning, there was an air raid alarm, but by now those are so common that
清晨，有一个空袭警报，但到现在为止，这些警报已经很普遍了，
they hardly register as more than routine.
他们几乎没有像常规那样注册。
And besides, the all clear has come through.
此外，一切都已经过去了。
Only a few planes were spotted, meaning this likely wasn't a bombing run.
只发现了几架飞机，这意味着这可能不是轰炸。
There's no real reason to believe that this day would be any worse than the last.
没有真正的理由相信这一天会比前一天更糟。
Other Japanese cities, notably Tokyo, have taken serious hits from bombing.
日本的其他城市，尤其是东京，受到炸弹袭击的严重打击。
But so far, your city, Hiroshima, has been comparatively fortunate--all but ignored by
但是到目前为止，您的城市广岛市还是比较幸运的，但几乎被所有人忽略了
the American B-29s.
美国的B-29
The total warfare Japan has been waging for over a decade has affected everyone in the
日本进行了十多年的全面战争影响了日本的每个人。
country in some way--when you were younger, you'd served overseas yourself.
在某个国家/地区-年轻的时候，您就自己在国外服务过。
Now, all these years later, it's almost surprising that you've been spared the worst tragedies
现在，这些年过去了，让您幸免于最惨烈的悲剧几乎令人惊讶
of the home front.
前面的
Most of all, you pray that the war will end before your son is old enough to fight, or
最重要的是，您祈祷战争将在您的儿子年纪大到可以打架之前结束，或者
daughter to be widowed.
女儿要丧偶。
For now, like the other teenagers, they've been occupied with civilian defense, helping
目前，像其他少年一样，他们一直忙于民防，
knock down old buildings to make way for military vehicles in the event of an invasion.
发生入侵时，拆除旧建筑物为军事车辆腾出空间。
A minute later: 8:15 am.
一分钟后：上午8:15。
You step into the lobby of the building.
您走进大楼的大厅。
And then the world changes.
然后世界改变了。
An incredible yellow light like the flash from a camera blazes all around you, and everything
令人难以置信的黄光，例如相机的闪光灯，将您周围的所有事物照亮
around you becomes an empty white.
你周围变成一个空白。
You're sent flying, and you feel pieces of debris strike you, followed by the deafening
你被送飞了，你感觉到碎片碎片击中你，然后震耳欲聋
boom as the sound from the explosion catches up.
爆炸声响起时，会产生轰动。
You slam against the floor and lose consciousness–probably just for a moment, you're not sure.
您猛烈地摔倒在地板上并失去意识-可能只是片刻，您不确定。
You know you need to get up.
你知道你需要起床。
Did you break any bones?
你骨折了吗？
No time to consider the situation.
没有时间考虑这种情况。
No one else is in the lobby with you, but all of the furniture has been blown to one
大厅里没有其他人陪着您，但是所有家具都被炸毁了。
side of the room, along with your body.
房间的一面，还有你的身体。
You push yourself up and step back outside through the door that's now missing all of
您将自己推上去，然后走出外面的门
its glass.
它的杯子。
You check all around yourself, and see what you're up against.
您检查自己周围的所有事物，然后看看自己在面对什么。
In front of you is a wall of fire, and it seems to be growing.
在您面前是一堵火墙，它似乎正在增长。
You turn to run the other way, but now the wind is against you, and the glass shards
你转身以另一种方式奔跑，但是现在风在逆着你，玻璃碎片
and pieces of rubble fly back toward the blaze in the most powerful storm you've ever felt.
在您所感受到的最强大的风暴中，瓦砾碎片飞向大火。
You duck back into the doorway and watch as anything that can catch fire, does.
你躲回门口，看着任何可能着火的东西。
Somehow, you'll have to fight the tremendous windstorm.
无论如何，您将不得不抗击巨大的风暴。
As you push forward, you catch glimpses of people who'd been outside during the blast,
向前推进时，您会瞥见爆炸期间曾在外面的人，
some lying dead in the street.
一些躺在街上死了。
The fingertips are the first part of the body to catch fire.
指尖是身体着火的第一部分。
Among the living, some are horribly burned.
在生活中，有些人被严重烧死。
The boiling wind blows strips of clothing off of them, along with strips of skin.
沸腾的风把衣服条和皮肤条吹掉。
Everyone just wants to get away from the fire.
每个人都只是想远离火源。
You feel like you might be getting burned yourself.
您感觉自己可能会被烧死。
There's the river in front of you.
你面前有条河。
Along with the pack of people pressing against you, you jump into the water.
随着一群人向你施压，您跳入水中。
When you rise above the surface to catch your breath, more debris rains down.
当您上升到地面上方以呼吸时，更多的碎屑会下雨。
How much time has passed?
多少时间过去了？
Are more bombs falling?
还会有更多炸弹落下吗？
You hear a child yelling, and help her get across to the other side of the river.
您会听到一个孩子大喊大叫，并帮助她越过河的另一边。
There are no more bombs, and although there are fires burning in all directions, the fireball
没有更多的炸弹，尽管有四面八方的大火在燃烧，但是火球
has stopped expanding, and the air isn't as hot.
停止膨胀，空气也不那么热。
You try to help people to their feet.
您尝试帮助人们站起来。
Some can manage, others can't.
有些可以管理，有些则不能。
A fire engine arrives, and the men start pulling anyone who can't walk onto the truck.
一辆消防车到了，这些人开始拉扯任何不能走上卡车的人。
You help as best you can, and then follow in the direction that the truck heads, along
您会尽力提供帮助，然后按照卡车行驶的方向行驶
with a small cohort of other people who've escaped the worst of the blast.
与一小群幸免于难的人。
Now, as you trek through piles of bricks, concrete, and metal, making your way back
现在，当您徒步穿越成堆的砖块，混凝土和金属时，回到过去
toward your house, the cloud cover thickens, and heavy drops of rain fall.
朝着你的房子，云层变厚，大雨滴落下。
They're black, apparently from soot.
它们是黑色的，显然来自烟灰。
Nothing is as important to you as finding out if your family is safe, but neither you
对您来说，没有什么比确定家人是否安全重要，但您
nor the other survivors can ignore the calls for help as you pass block upon block of leveled
当您逐级通过时，其他幸存者也不会忽略求助电话
buildings amid the smoke and fire.
建筑物在烟雾和火焰中。
For hours, as you press northward through the smoke and wreckage, and burning houses,
数小时，当您向北按烟尘和残骸，烧毁房屋时，
you hear the cries of people trapped below buildings.
您会听到有人被困在建筑物下面的呼声。
When you can, you free them from the debris.
如果可以的话，可以将它们从碎片中解放出来。
Others, you're powerless to help.
其他人，您无能为力。
You pass countless stumbling, crawling, prostrate, or dead.
您经历了无数绊脚石，爬行，下垂或死亡。
You bury your guilt, and try not to see the worst.
您掩饰了内，并尽量避免看到最糟糕的情况。
You press forward in what you're fairly sure is the direction of your neighborhood.
向前推，您肯定会确定附近的方向。
A little girl is wandering, clutching at a wound on her head.
一个小女孩徘徊，抓着头上的伤口。
You refuse to pass her by, and for a mile you carry her, until you reach a makeshift
您拒绝路过她，并且将她抱了一英里，直到达到临时状态
clinic inside a school that, aside from its windows, is largely intact.
学校内部的诊所，除了窗户外，基本上还完好无损。
Later you'll learn that you were among the closest people to the atomic blast who didn't
稍后，您将了解到您是原子弹爆炸中最亲密的人之一
die.
死。
The building you were in shielded you from the full force of the blast and heat.
您所在的建筑物使您免受爆炸和热浪的冲击。
Anyone within a half mile who was exposed to the initial blast of heat didn't merely
半英里之内暴露于高温之下的任何人都不仅仅是
burn to death: they were instantly incinerated.
烧死：立即被焚化。
Outside that radius, thousands more burned to death, or died from the flying debris and
在这个半径之外，还有成千上万的人被烧死，或者死于飞扬的碎片和
falling buildings.
倒塌的建筑物。
Here in the elementary school, people are already stretched out shoulder-to-shoulder
在小学里，人们已经肩并肩伸展
on the floor.
在地上。
A few nurses scramble from person to person, cleaning the worst wounds, but apparently
一些护士在人与人之间争先恐后，清理了最严重的伤口，但显然
already without enough bandages for everyone.
已经没有足够的绷带给所有人。
Some of the charred bodies have clearly already stopped breathing.
一些烧焦的尸体显然已经停止呼吸。
All of the emergency planning in the city, setting up emergency aid centers with supplies
市内所有紧急计划，建立配备物资的紧急援助中心
in the various sectors of the city, had assumed there would actually be a city left after
在城市的各个部门中，假设已经存在了一个城市
an attack.
攻击。
Most of the adults are stoical in their suffering, but from the cries of children, it's clear
多数成年人痛苦难忍，但从孩子们的哭声中可以明显看出
that there's little medicine for the pain.
止痛药很少。
As you scan the unbelievable ranks of bodies on the mats, desperately hoping not to see
当您扫描垫子上难以置信的尸体等级时，拼命希望不要看到
anyone familiar, you see the full extent of their injuries.
任何熟悉的人，您都会看到他们受伤的全部范围。
Many are so badly burned you can't imagine that they'll survive.
许多人被烧得如此惨烈，以至于他们无法生存。
Apparently, people who were wearing dark colored clothing were sometimes burned more than those
显然，穿着深色衣服的人有时比被烧伤的人更多。
wearing white, because of the difference in heat absorption.
穿着白色，因为吸收热量的差异。
With uncontrollable tears of relief, you learn that no one in your own family is among them.
带着无法控制的眼泪，您知道自己家里没有人。
Three miles from miles from the center of the city, your family's wooden house was destroyed,
距离市中心三英里，您家的木屋被毁，
but hadn't caught fire, at least not yet.
但尚未起火，至少尚未起火。
You're frightened when you realize that your wife has been bleeding, cut down her back
当您意识到妻子流血时，您会感到恐惧
and sides by glass shards, but she assures you that the injuries are all on the surface,
和侧面有玻璃碎片，但她向您保证，伤害全部在表面，
and takes you by the hand, to your son and daughter, both of whom are trying to administer
并把您带到您的儿子和女儿，这两个儿子都试图管理
some aid to the wounded.
对伤者的一些帮助。
There's no actual ointment left, and they're making due with cooking oil, which is better
没有实际的药膏了，他们正在用食用油来做，这更好
than nothing, albeit disturbing, given what's happened.
考虑到发生了什么事，什么都不是，尽管令人不安。
They've both suffered bruises and cuts, but their greatest pain was waiting for you to
他们都遭受了擦伤和割伤，但是他们最大的痛苦就是等着你
return.
返回。
They'd been certain that since you were in the city center, you must have been killed.
他们已经确定，自从您在市中心以来，您一定已经被杀害。
For your part, you're glad you've been able to keep your children healthy as they've grown
就您而言，您很高兴能够随着孩子的成长保持健康
up.
起来。
Other young people at the clinic have become weak as the rationing has gotten worse, and
随着配给情况的恶化，诊所中的其他年轻人变得虚弱，并且
you can see that among the injured, malnutrition is going to make their chances of survival
您会看到，在营养不良的人中，营养不良将使他们生存的机会
much less likely.
可能性要小得多。
Now that you've found your family, you can go back out and help with the rescue.
现在您已经找到了家人，您可以回去帮助救援。
You can't see much organized effort beyond the continuing lines of evacuees, but along
除了持续的撤离人员，您看不到有组织的工作，但是
with other individuals, you try to move as many of the injured as you can.
与其他人一起，您要设法移动尽可能多的伤者。
Some wounded people are stuck on a sandbar by the river, and you help to lift them to
一些受伤的人被卡在河边的沙洲上，您可以帮助将他们抬到
higher ground before the tide rises.
潮涨之前，先将地面升高。
In one particularly gruesome instance, the body of a victim slips from your hands as
在一个特别可怕的情况下，受害者的身体从您的手中滑落，因为
the burned skin of the arm tears loose.
烧伤的手臂皮肤的泪水松弛。
After several more hours, you begin feeling weak, and wander back to the aid station.
再过几个小时后，您开始感到虚弱，然后回到援助站。
By the time you get there, you realize that, broken bones or no, you haven't escaped unharmed.
当您到达那里时，您已经意识到，骨头骨折或没有骨折，您并没有幸免于难。
It can't just be exhaustion catching up with you.
不能只用精疲力尽追赶你。
You're lightheaded, and feel weak, like you've come down with the flu.
您头晕目眩，感到虚弱，就像感染了流感一样。
You sit down on a cot, just to catch your breath.
您坐在一张婴儿床上，只是为了喘口气。
You feel feverish.
你发烧了。
A nurse offers a cup of water, which you gratefully accept.
护士请您喝杯水，我们感激不尽。
But as you pour the cool liquid past your lips, you can't swallow it.
但是，当您将凉爽的液体倒在嘴唇上时，就无法吞咽。
Embarrassed, you cough and spit it out.
不好意思，你咳嗽然后吐出来。
You feel much worse all of a sudden, and without hesitation begin to vomit on the floor.
突然之间，您会感到更糟，并且毫不犹豫地开始呕吐在地板上。
Someone puts a wastebasket next to you to catch it.
有人把废纸ket放在你旁边抓住它。
You weren't the first with this symptom, nor will you be alone as you continue to retch
您不是第一个出现这种症状的人，也不会孤单，继续前进
and suffer diarrhea for days on end.
连续几天腹泻。
Aid workers are distributing soft rice biscuits and bowls of rice porridge, but, like you,
援助人员正在分发柔软的大米饼干和一碗稀饭，但像您一样，
many people have little appetite.
很多人食欲不振。
As days pass, insects find the necrotic tissue on the survivors.
随着时间的流逝，昆虫会在幸存者身上发现坏死组织。
Horrified family members do their best to clear the wounds of larvae.
受惊的家庭成员会尽力清除幼虫的伤口。
You're embarrassed to have your wife and children caring for you.
让您的妻子和孩子照顾您很尴尬。
It's supposed to be the other way around.
应该是相反的方式。
After a couple of days of misery, the nausea subsides.
经过几天的痛苦，恶心消退了。
How could it not?
怎么可能不呢
You haven't eaten in days.
你好几天没吃饭了。
It takes courage, but you're able to take tiny sips of water, and then a bite or two
这需要勇气，但您可以喝一小口水，然后一两口
of porridge.
粥
It's rare to get a moment with a doctor, but from what you can overhear, you've been hit
很少有时间和医生见面，但是从您可以偷听到的东西来看，您已经受到打击
with sickness caused by an invisible kind of force called gamma rays that can fly right
由一种叫做伽马射线的看不见的力引起的疾病
through your body, ripping tissues apart.
通过您的身体，撕开组织。
As your strength recovers, you again try to make yourself useful aiding in the endless
随着力量的恢复，您将再次尝试使自己成为无尽的帮助者
recovery work.
恢复工作。
Often that means helping to carry bodies to the perpetual funeral pyres.
通常，这意味着帮助将尸体运送到永久的葬礼堆。
Many of these unfortunates never got to say goodbye to their families, and their loved
这些不幸中的许多人从未与家人和亲人道别
ones will never know what became of their remains.
那些人永远不会知道他们遗骸变成了什么。
For some victims, the poisoning from radiation was much worse.
对于某些受害者而言，辐射中毒的情况更加严重。
By the 24 hour mark, several had become incoherent from damage to the brain.
到24小时大关，有几只因大脑受损而变得不连贯。
Others had a racing heart; some soon suffered a heart attack.
其他人有一颗竞速的心。一些不久后心脏病发作。
Some literally changed color, turning bright red as if sunburned.
一些颜色实际上发生了变化，变成鲜红色，好像被晒伤了。
Those who, unlike you, never recovered their appetite, were dead in a few days.
那些和您不一样的人，食欲不振，几天之内就死了。
But then something especially worrying begins.
但是随后开始特别令人担忧的事情。
Several people who had been up and about are now again lying flat on the cots, and they
几个已经起床的人现在又平躺在婴儿床上，他们
don't look good.
不好看
Their skin has become mottled with purple blotches as blood vessels break.
随着血管破裂，他们的皮肤变得斑驳，有紫色斑点。
Again they feel weak and sick.
他们再次感到虚弱和不适。
The pain already looks like too much to bear, but then it gets worse.
这种痛苦看起来已经难以承受，但随后变得更加严重。
The dying vomit blood, and blood flows from their anus.
垂死的呕吐血液，血液从肛门流出。
Even the eyes begin to bleed.
甚至眼睛也开始流血。
By now additional medical workers have come from the outskirts and outside the prefecture.
到目前为止，郊区和县外都有更多的医务工作者。
But those who hover over death tend to have shriveled veins, so they can't even receive
但是那些徘徊在死亡之上的人往往会萎缩静脉，因此他们甚至无法接受
morphine.
吗啡。
You hope that you're not due to follow their downward slide.
您希望您不要跟随他们的下滑。
A doctor examines you, and notices spots on your body that you'd overlooked.
医生会对您进行检查，并发现您身体上被忽视的斑点。
It's happening.
正在发生。
But at least for now you don't feel it, and you're able to carry on a conversation.
但是至少现在您还没有感觉到，并且可以进行对话。
The doctor has come from Tokyo.
医生是东京来的。
He must be an expert on this kind of disease, although before the bombing of Hiroshima and
他必须是这种疾病的专家，尽管在广岛和
Nagasaki, there were very few cases--mostly scientists doing research with radium or other
长崎（Nagasaki）的病例很少-大多数科学家是用镭或其他元素进行研究
unusual substances.
不寻常的物质。
He confirms that the atomic bomb blast dosed you with harmful radiation.
他确认原子弹爆炸给您带来了有害的辐射。
In that conversation, and many more that would follow over the years, you avidly learn details
在这段对话中，以及接下来的许多年中，您将热衷于了解详细信息
about radiation.
关于辐射。
The blast did emit gamma rays, and X-rays as well.
爆炸确实发出了伽马射线，也发出了X射线。
They're slightly different, but the main thing to know is that in a high enough strength,
它们略有不同，但主要要知道的是，在足够高的强度下，
they're both very bad for you, unlike the relatively weak X-rays that doctors use to
它们对您都非常有害，不像医生用来比较弱的X射线
take pictures of your bones.
给你的骨头拍照。
Both X-rays and gamma rays are made of photons, the same kind of wave-particle as regular
X射线和γ射线都是由光子构成的，与常规
beams of light.
光束。
But they have a much shorter wavelength, and very different properties from visible light,
但是它们的波长要短得多，而且与可见光的特性大不相同，
as far as people are concerned.
就人们而言。
By comparison, some of the people who are recovering from serious burns to the skin
相比之下，一些从严重灼伤中恢复过来的人
also received a very, very heavy amount of long wavelength, infrared radiation, which
还收到了非常大量的长波长红外辐射
causes matter to heat up--in this case, a great deal.
导致物质变热-在这种情况下，会产生很大的变化。
The temperature of the blast was thousands of degrees--enough to reduce people to dust
爆炸的温度是几千度-足以减少人们的灰尘
in an instant.
顷刻。
Although gamma rays don't cause surface burns, they're an example of what's called ionizing
尽管伽玛射线不会引起表面灼伤，但它们只是所谓电离的一个例子
radiation.
辐射。
Non-ionizing radiation, like the signals that a radio antenna picks up, doesn't seem to
非电离辐射，例如无线电天线接收到的信号，似乎没有
have much effect of living tissue at everyday doses.
每天服用都会对活组织产生很大影响。
But ionizing radiation is another story.
但是电离辐射是另一回事。
This class gets its name from its invisible effect, which is to cause an atom to lose
此类的名称来自其无形的作用，即导致原子丢失
electrons, leaving positively charged ions.
电子，留下带正电的离子。
Inside the cells of your body are complex molecules held together by electrons, and
人体细胞内部是由电子结合在一起的复杂分子，并且
if enough of the molecules are torn apart, the cell dies.
如果足够多的分子被撕裂，细胞就会死亡。
This is especially bad when it happens in bone marrow, which manufactures blood cells
当它发生在制造血细胞的骨髓中时，这尤其糟糕
for the body.
为身体。
A deficiency of red blood cells deprives the body of oxygen.
红细胞缺乏会剥夺人体的氧气。
Low white blood cell count leaves the body vulnerable to infection.
白细胞计数低会使身体容易感染。
And too few platelets prevents blood from clotting, which causes the characteristic
血小板太少会阻止血液凝结，从而导致血液流变
blotches in addition to other ill effects.
除了其他不良影响外，还会出现斑点。
In addition to gamma and X-rays, there are streams of particles called beta rays, which
除了伽玛射线和X射线，还有称为β射线的粒子流，
are loose electrons.
是松散的电子。
Alpha rays, the charged nuclei of helium atoms, and loose neutrons, fly out of unstable elements
Alpha射线，氦原子的带电原子核和松散的中子从不稳定的元素中飞出
as they decay.
随着它们的衰变。
A few pounds of one such element, uranium, was the fuel for the atom bomb at Hiroshima.
几磅这种铀元素就是广岛原子弹的燃料。
Another, plutonium, powered the blast at Nagasaki.
另一枚powered为长崎的爆炸提供了动力。
Both elements proved terribly effective at creating a chain reaction.
事实证明，这两种元素在产生连锁反应方面都非常有效。
Moreover, it's not safe to even handle much of these substances for any length of time
而且，即使在任何时间段内都不能处理很多这类物质是不安全的
without protection.
没有保护。
Marie Curie, who had discovered many of the important properties of radioactivity had
玛丽·居里（Marie Curie）发现了许多重要的放射性物质的特性
herself later died of radiation poisoning.
自己后来死于辐射中毒。
So amid the smoke and dust from the nuclear explosion was a mass of radioactive particles
因此，在核爆炸产生的烟雾和尘埃中，有大量放射性粒子
blasted into the air.
吹向空中。
Some of that material fell right back down in the black rain.
在黑雨中，其中一些物质立即落下。
If you have radioactive material on your skin or clothes you can spread it around.
如果您的皮肤或衣服上有放射性物质，您可以将其散布在周围。
Worse, if you ingest radioactive dust, it can stay in your system for some time, and
更糟糕的是，如果摄入放射性粉尘，它可能会在系统中停留一段时间，并且
for awhile at least, your body could itself give off radiation.
至少有一段时间，您的身体本身可能会发出辐射。
You think about how you held your wife and children, and now wish you hadn't found them
您想想如何抱住妻子和孩子，现在希望您没有找到他们
so quickly.
这么快。
Because the blast was so far above ground, there wouldn't be a dangerous concentration
因为爆炸距离地面很远，所以不会有危险的集中
at the center--one small comfort in the chaos.
在中心-混乱中的一点舒适感。
For weeks, you do decline in health.
数周以来，您的健康状况确实会下降。
You're admitted to a real hospital this time.
您这次被送进了一家真正的医院。
All your hair falls out, and your skin becomes swollen.
您的所有头发脱落，并且皮肤变得肿胀。
The nausea comes back.
恶心回来了。
People continue to die.
人们继续死亡。
By September, some of the burn victims are in better shape.
到9月，一些烧伤受害者的状况有所好转。
You assume that those with both heavy burns and radiation poisoning are dead by now.
您假设到现在，既有严重烧伤又有辐射中毒的人已经死亡。
But you do not die.
但是你不会死。
Over the years, your family builds a new life, utterly thankful that you didn't share the
多年来，您的家人过着新的生活，非常感谢您没有分享
fate of more than 200,000 in the two devastated cities.
在两个被摧毁的城市中，超过20万的命运。
You return to work for some time, and then retire on a pension.
您会重新工作一段时间，然后退休。
Your son and daughter both marry, and each begins to build their own family.
您的儿子和女儿都结婚，并且每个人都开始建立自己的家庭。
You learn about a special kind of chemical in the body called DNA, which scientists have
您将了解体内一种称为DNA的特殊化学物质
found contains all the blueprints for the cells in your body, and that combines with
找到的包含您体内细胞的所有设计图，并与
the DNA from your spouse to build a new person in a woman's womb.
您配偶的DNA在女人的子宫中建立一个新人。
You also learn that it's damage to DNA that causes cancer, and you know that cancer rates
您还了解到导致癌症的原因是DNA的损伤，并且您知道癌症发生率
are especially high for people exposed to radiation.
对于暴露在辐射下的人来说尤其高。
You're not worried so much for yourself as for your children.
您不必为自己和孩子那么担心。
Although they may not have displayed acute radiation sickness, they were certainly exposed
尽管他们可能没有表现出急性放射病，但他们肯定已经暴露
to gamma rays.
伽玛射线
And if DNA is damaged, might their children not have inherited the mutated genes?
如果DNA受损，他们的孩子可能不会继承突变的基因吗？
Certainly, some babies born soon after the bombing had a high rate of birth defects,
当然，轰炸后不久出生的一些婴儿的出生缺陷率很高，
like underdeveloped brains.
像不发达的大脑。
So far, no one has seen any evidence of genetic damaged passed on to children of hibakusha--atom
到目前为止，还没有人看到任何遗传损伤的证据传给hibakusha--atom儿童
bomb survivors--who weren't exposed in utero.
炸弹幸存者-未在子宫内暴露的人。
You make sure that your children and theirs get check-ups from the doctor, and the new,
您要确保您的孩子和他们的孩子得到医生的检查，并且新来的孩子，
more peaceful Japanese government is keeping tabs on their health, and yours of course.
更和平的日本政府会密切关注他们的健康，当然也要关注您的健康。
You can't help but notice that people in your new neighborhood in Tokyo don't want to stand
您忍不住注意到东京新街区的人们不想站起来
close to anyone in your family, and although their fears are unfounded, you can understand
与家人中的任何人都亲密无间，尽管他们的恐惧是没有根据的，但您可以理解
their wariness in such strange times.
他们在如此陌生的时代保持警惕。
And you follow the arms race, as nations build nuclear weapons that could somehow inflict
随着军备竞赛的发展，各国制造的核武器可能会以某种方式造成
far more damage than the one you experienced.
比您经历的伤害大得多。
Years later, you take your grandchildren to see a movie you've heard about.
数年后，您带孙子去看电影。
In this movie, there's a reptile whose body is altered by radiation, turning it into a
在这部电影中，有一个爬行动物，其身体被辐射改变，变成了一个爬行动物。
monster that destroys the city of Tokyo.
摧毁东京市的怪物。
It's a bit of dramatic license, you know, but that's what movies are for.
您知道这有点戏剧性，但这就是电影的目的。
The kids are old enough that they try not to seem scared, although clearly the fire-breathing
孩子们已经足够大了，尽管看上去很火，他们还是尽量不显得害怕。
beast makes quite an impression on them.
野兽给他们留下了深刻的印象。
The allegory in the movie is not lost on you, although you decide not to share it with these
尽管您决定不与这些人分享影片中的寓言，但您并不会因此而失去
children of a new era.
新时代的孩子们。
They're aware of their country's bitter, foolish experience in making war, and the awful toll
他们意识到自己国家在战争中的痛苦，愚蠢的经历以及可怕的伤亡
that their parents witnessed when men tested the limits of human suffering.
他们的父母亲眼见证了人类测试人类苦难的极限。
But you hope with all your heart that they will themselves only ever see such horror
但是您全心全意地希望他们自己只会看到如此恐怖
in a movie.
在电影中。
This story is a composite sketch based upon the firsthand accounts of survivors of Hiroshima.
这个故事是根据广岛幸存者的第一手资料合成的。
Do you know anyone who’s had to deal with heavy radiation, either for work or for a
您知道有人在工作或工作中不得不面对大量辐射吗？
medical treatment--or through exposure to hazardous material?
医疗-或通过接触有害物质？
Let us know what you think in the comments.
请在留言中让我们知道你的想法。
Also, be sure to check out our other video called “What To Do If There’s a Nuclear
另外，请务必查看我们的其他视频“如果有核武器该怎么办”
Explosion.”
爆炸。”
Thanks for watching, and, as always, don’t forget to like, share, and subscribe.
感谢您的收看，而且一如既往，不要忘记喜欢，分享和订阅。
See you next time!
下次见！